[ARIEL]
Sorry, Pearl.
He doesn't owe
me an explanation.
Pearl doesn't seem okay.
Tantan, she’s fine.
Join us tomorrow
at Cabitoonan, okay?
- We're planting mangroves.
- Sure.
[ARIEL] Let’s go! One, two, three!
Let's start planting!
- [CAROL] Let’s go!
- [CROWD CHEERING]
[JAO] You know, Kara,
you should plant the first one
because this project won't
be possible without you.
Let Egay do it!
- Egay!
- Egay.
[KARA] Give your
mangrove a name, too.
[EGAY] How about Karajao?
Like your baby.
[CROWD]
Team Mangroves forever!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[CROWD CHANTING]
Team Mangroves!
[MAN]
Let's go!
[CROWD CHANTING]
Team Mangroves!
[KARA]
Who did this?
Ma’am Vida!
We got a call from
the new landowner.
New owner?
It had already been
sold to a corporation.
[JAO] I can already hear my
boss's voice in my head, saying...
that everything is
legal and aboveboard.
Kara, look at this.
[MIKA] Sir, please call me.
I just discovered something.
[MAN]
Jao!
- Sir?
- How are you?
[PAUL CHUCKLES]
What are you doing here?
Why didn't you tell me?
I have some news for you!
Couldn't you tell me
over the phone, sir?
You had to fly all
the way to Siargao?
Are you mad at me?
[JAO AND PAUL LAUGH]
No, sir.
I’m just surprised you’re here.
Well, that’s good because
I have a surprise for you.
You wanted to stay in
Siargao longer, right?
Sir?
See, our CEO acquired a new property
here in Barangay Cabitoonan.
In General Luna.
That’s how you
pronounce it, right?
[PAUL LAUGHS]
Wait, wait, sir.
Barangay Cabitoonan…
the one next to the
mangrove plantation?
Yes.
And you’re the project lead!
Wait, wait, wait, sir.
Are you serious?
[PAUL LAUGHS]
Why would I joke
about these things?
Sir, that lot is
the same spot...
the locals are
fighting to protect
as part of the mangrove
reserve expansion.
You know, the upper management
is aware of all this, okay?
That’s why I’m here, aren’t I?
What do you mean?
They know that you’re
part of the opposing side.
Wait. Opposing side?
So you really see the locals defending the
mangroves of the island as the opposition?
Listen, okay?
Our company has the property
rights to that land, okay?
Once we prove
regulatory compliance,
once we resolve the
dispute, this project proceeds.
Okay? That’s why I want
you and they want you
to stay away from the NGO
that opposes this whole project.
Just think about it.
It’s a great opportunity.
All the socio-economic benefits
that can come from this project.
This is so good!
I can’t be part
of this project, sir.
I resign.
What?
You can’t resign!
I don’t accept your resignation!
Okay? I know you're emotional
right now, so just calm down.
I understand this.
But you, of all people, know
how important this will
be for the community!
We’re not doing
anything illegal.
Okay? This is aboveboard.
[ALON BY JL]
- [PHONE RINGS]
- [JAO BREATHES DEEPLY]
[PHONE RINGS]
Kara, please pick up.
[PHONE CONTINUES RINGING]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello? Carol?
[CAROL ON THE PHONE]
Hello, Jao.
Is Kara with you?
I can't reach her.
[CAROL ON THE PHONE]
No.
But I ran into her earlier
when she was on her way to the
GL municipal office with Attorney Noah.
They said they were going to see the mayor
about the mangrove site in Cabitoonan.
Okay.
Thank you, Carol.
Is there something
you want to tell me?
Kara, I just found out.
Project head?
How could you be
the project head?
- Were you even going to tell me?
- [JAO] Of course.
But can you please
trust me on this?
[KARA] How can I
trust you right now?
Kara, look.
I honestly had no idea
they’d make me project head...
for this project.
That's how my boss works.
He can assign any
development head he wants
to projects that
come under him.
I resigned as soon
as I found out, but...
he wouldn’t let me.
I also thought it might be
better if I led it because…
I can make sure that
everything is legal and...
Legal?
Do you hear yourself?
‘Cause right now,
you sound exactly like your boss.
[FOOTSTEPS WALKING DOWN STAIRS]
[NEWS REPORTER ON VIDEO]
It’s been years since
Super Typhoon Odette
devastated Siargao,
but its impact remains fresh
in the minds of Siargaonons.
Odette first made landfall on Siargao,
subjecting the island to its full force.
The storm caused over
20 billion pesos in damage...
Without those mangroves,
Typhoon Odette would have
hit the island even harder.
[SIARGAONON]
Exactly, Mom!
So I understand
how frustrating it is
that Jao ended up
heading the resort
that put the mangrove
expansion on hold.
What you're feeling
right now, Kara,
must hurt worse than
getting cheated on.
[KARA]
Not at all.
I believe him when
he said he didn’t know.
So, technically,
he didn’t do anything wrong.
It's just unfortunate that,
even if it wasn't intentional,
I'm finding out that
the people I trust
are the ones who
aren't on my side.
[CAROL]
Hey! Don't say that!
Don't compare Jao to
your ex, Jeremy, okay?
Your ex was a liar and a user.
Jao's different, okay?
But I can't help
having doubts.
Jao and I haven't
been together that long.
I knew Jeremy for so long,
and look what happened.
What if the same
thing happens with Jao?
That's why it's so
hard to trust men.
Right, Pearl?
[CAROL] Even after
my husband left me,
I still believe...
all men are different
Some are bad...
[SIARGAONON]
...but some are good.
Even if they make the same
choices or act the same way,
we have to understand
their motivations.
That's what really
sets them apart.
I was actually scared to
ask Jao which he'd choose.
His job or Siargao.
Kara.
Do you really mean
Siargao or you?
This is bigger than me, Pearl.
So please,
come with me tomorrow.
- Of course.
- Yeah.
[ARIEL] They'll get through this
because they're Kara and Jao.
Right?
As in, awesome!
Amazing!
I don’t know.
But I understand Kara.
I actually feel bad for her.
[SIARGAONON]
That’s true.
[TEXT MESSAGE]
Sir Han, how are you? Are you okay?
Please reply.
[TEXT MESSAGE]
I hope your family’s okay. I hope you’re okay.
[ARIEL]
Hey.
You’re awfully quiet.
What’s going on with you?
Princess Pearl!
Hey.
You okay?
I’m already helping you out!
I don’t even work here!
[KARA]
Just think about it.
It'll be a huge problem
once the resort is operational.
Exactly!
And do you know why mangroves
are so important to your community?
First of all, these trees
help hold the soil together
and prevent erosion
from the water's flow.
They also filter out dirt,
sediment, and pollutants
before they reach the sea.
But most importantly,
they're our best defense
against storms and floods.
Those trees aren't just trees.
They're protecting our community.
And they're our legacy
for the next generation.
So I hope we can all
support Project Mangrove.
And let's never
let them build that resort.
I hope we can count
on your support.
[MAN]
That's right.
I don't want another
Typhoon Odette.
[SIARGAONON]
We'll do whatever we can to help.
Thank you.
[MAN 2]
Don't worry, ma'am.
We'll help you.
[CROWD]
That's right!
All right.
We'll collect your signatures
and send them to
the Coastal Office.
[PEARL]
Here you go.
- Thank you.
[ARIEL] Maybe you can
share these with other people.
[ARIEL] Kara's incredible, Mom.
She never gets tired.
I think we've been to
every barangay in GL!
[CAROL CHUCKLES]
Thanks for coming with me.
Of course.
We're your sidekicks.
- Want some more?
- I'll take this.
I'm good. Thanks.
Jao!
Eat!
- [ARIEL] Jao, eat up.
- [JAO] Good evening.
[CAROL]
Get him a plate.
Aren't you getting
my messages?
I've been trying to
reach you all day.
I haven't checked
my phone.
I’m busy.
Thanks to your company.
I have to expedite
the mangrove permits.
Kara, can we please
be mature about this?
Why?
What did I say?
Are you mad at me?
Are you going to
argue with me?
If I need to.
Jao, I can’t let this pass.
Kara, you have to trust me.
This project can’t
move forward, Jao.
Hey, it's not that simple.
I know my boss.
He always finds workarounds
to make things happen.
Are you afraid of him?
Why would I be afraid?
I'm just being rational
and professional about this!
I know what I'm doing!
And you know
where I stand, right?
Hey, wait.
[SIARGAONON]
That's enough.
Don’t fight.
[CAROL] You two aren't the
ones who get to decide this!
[CAROL] Better yet,
let's set up a meeting
with the locals
affected by this.
I'll talk to the captain, okay?
[CAROL] Let's hear
what the people think.
Listen to them first.
Instead of...
arguing with each other.
Good idea.
You should eat.
We still have fish.
[ARIEL IN SIARGAONON]
Thank you so much for coming, everyone.
Thank you also
to Captain Gani
for helping organize
this meeting.
We're here to hear from
the residents of Cabitoonan
about the proposed luxury
resort by Young Horizon Builders,
which Pure Coast opposes.
Pure Coast wants to
preserve the property
as part of the mangrove
reserve expansion.
Here to represent Young Horizon
Builders is Mr. Jao Calderon.
[CLAPPING]
And representing Pure Coast
is Ms. Kara De Leon.
[CLAPPING]
Kara, Jao, please start.
No need to be formal.
Sounds good.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Thank you all for coming.
It shows how much you
care about the island.
[SIARGAONON]
Good morning.
Kara’s right.
We're here to
hear your thoughts
on the luxury resort
proposed for Cabitoonan,
which will certainly provide
jobs for the local residents.
[OLD LADY] You two
look good together.
Oh, we're very different.
Way different.
[CROWD GIGGLING]
We hope you'll support
Pure Coast's goal
of planting more mangroves
here in Cabitoonan.
We all know how
important mangroves are
in protecting us from storms.
At Young Horizon Builders,
you can rest assured we'll
carefully study this project
to ensure we comply
with all environmental laws.
You can also rest assured
that we'll hire locally
for both construction
and resort operations.
We all know your
company's track record.
It can’t keep a single promise.
Sure, they'll have jobs.
But then what?
Will the resort protect
them when a storm hits?
[LOCAL]
Exactly! We'll have jobs,
but how can we work
if we're dead, right?
[CROWD MURMURING IN AGREEMENT]
[ARIEL] Okay...
Thank you, everyone.
We're here to see who supports
the project and who doesn't.
[ARIEL] We'll be collecting
your signatures...
Good job.
Are you deliberately provoking me
to make me attack your company?
[LOCAL]
So once the resort is finished...
I'm just proud, Kara,
to see you fight for
what you believe in.
[BACKGROUND CHATTER]
[LOCAL]
That’s right.
But isn't it more important to
protect human lives as well as nature?
[CROWD MURMURING IN AGREEMENT]
[ARIEL] Okay, so for those who
agree with our appeal or protest letter...
So this is Sir Han's room.
You'd never guess he's rich.
No wonder he
always smells so good.
Especially his breath!
[ARIEL]
Life is hard,
so a lot of locals are counting
on jobs once the resort is built.
We can't judge them because
we don't know their circumstances.
We just need to make sure they
understand the consequences.
[ARIEL SIGHS]
[SIARGAONON]
That's true.
You really just have to
choose your hard, right?
[PAUL]
Kara, right?
Yes?
I’m Paul.
Jao’s boss.
Excuse me.
[PAUL CLEARS THROAT]
Oh...
I'm not invited.
Five million?
10 million.
Name your price.
You know,
in this digital age,
news travels fast.
Ms. Caitlyn De Leon?
That’s your name, right?
You can change your name
but the past will always
come back after you.
Release it.
Make sure peak hours.
[ARIEL SPEAKS SIARGAONON]
Oh, my god!
That woman’s just an outsider.
She doesn't care
about the island's future.
I think people need
to hear your side.
Your ally is my enemy.
You might as well tell
me you don't need me.
I need you.
But not for the
reasons that you think.
Headquarters asked
for your contact info.
They want to offer you the
international field officer position.
Is that the one with
headquarters in Denmark?
You're going
international, Kara!
But if I take it,
I'll have to leave the island?